Information about GDPR
======================

What is the GDPR?

The GDPR is a law in the European Union that regulates personal data privacy and security. It came into effect in EU member states on May 25, 2018. It replaces the Data Protection Directive and applies to every business that resides in the EU and deals with personal data or handles the data of people who are in the EU. At the core of the GDPR is the aim of simplifying, unifying, and updating the protection of personal data and guaranteeing that people stay within their rights and freedoms when providing their data.

What constitutes personal data?

Under GDPR, your name, location data, date of birth, and contact information are classified as your personal data by the GDPR. In fact, any information that is connected to a specific person in the EU can be classified as personal data.

What have you changed in your products to be ready for the GDPR?

Respecting and protecting customer privacy is one of our fundamental principles, and we process only what data is necessary for product functionality to perform as promised. That’s why to comply with the GDPR, just a few additional measures have been taken so that our solutions offer users granular control over what data they provide to Kaspersky through the agreements they accept.

Do products for Europe and other countries differ?

Identical products offered in Europe and other countries do not differ in terms of the protection they provide. All Kaspersky products operate within the agreements accepted for their use. For the products offered in Europe, the structure of agreements and of the respective consents obtained may differ slightly to be compliant with the GDPR.

What should I do if I live in Europe and already use your products?

We are trying to notify all of our current customers in Europe what they should do through all available channels: e-mail, in-product messages, push notifications, and so on. You can always visit our [website](https://www.kaspersky.com/) to get the latest GDPR-ready version of your product.

What happens if I travel from or to Europe?

Your product will continue to operate within the accepted agreements.
